What was that?
Kawachi
Yeah... Sure...
I was just about to get up...
Oh, I see. Got it.
Don't worry about it.
We'll meet to bargain with them early next week, all right?
Talk to you later.
My maternal grandfather died last night.
That dream I had...
Was that Grandpa...
and Mom?
Seems he'd lost touch with all of the relatives...
I come back after all this time and it's for a funeral...
I dunno about tomorrow.
It's different than a sacrifice. Something's off.
I don't think it's like some penalty game.
So, why? I don't get it at all.
I'm a little bit unsatisfied, but your presence
right now is more than just important.
There's no such thing in this world
as something never-ending.
Crying isn't painful, it's love's sweet drops, sweet drops!
I want to keep dreaming forever, ya know?
I want to be more kind, ya know?
As long as I’m with you, I’m happy.
Girls sure are strong, ya know?
But sometimes we're weak, ya know?
Our wish is to be happy, happy, happy!
And those days will be happy, too!
Just wanna make you happy!
I'm here.
Oh, Daikichi, you got here fast.
Just put your bags in Grandpa's room.
Okay.
By the way, there was a girl in the yard.
I can't remember, is Haruko's girl that age?
That wasn't Reina-chan...
Whose kid is she?
Darn it! This kitchen is so inconvenient!
I don't know what to do from here on out...
Well, he was 79 and died a peaceful death, didn't he?
Apparently, that girl is Grandpa's illegitimate child...
Hah?!
Grandpa's child?!
Grandpa didn't say a thing about it...
And his lover took off, too...
His lover?! He was 79!
It's so embarrassing, not to mention shameful...
Then she's...
Like your little sister...
And my aunt...
How can you make light of this?!
You're 30 years old! Old enough not to make such thoughtless remarks!
You died at peace, huh, Grandpa?
About how much should I put in?
[ Note: It's traditional to give
money as a condolence gift ]
As much as you like. It can be any amount.
I know, but there's a certain standard amount, isn't there?
Honestly, any amount is fine...
Although these days, it's very common for sutras to be recited
[ Note: For which services,
the priest is to be paid ]
and a posthumous Buddhist name to be given...
She said 400,000 to 500,000 yen.
That's a large sum of money.
Hello. It's been a long time.
Oh, Daikichi. Long time no see.
Have you been busy?
Yes, busy enough...
You always say you're busy! Too busy to visit your own mother...
He didn't even come home for New Year's.
Stop running! Reina!
Stop it! Reina!
Haruko!
Oh, Dai-chan! Long time no see!
Mama!
Reina!
Gotcha!
Now be a good girl and don't run around!
No way! I don't wanna!
What?
Nothing...
You look a lot like your grandfather when he was younger...
Daikichi, did you hear?
Yeah, from my mom earlier...
I wonder if it's true.
I'm sure my elder brother was lonely living alone, but...
Apparently, there's a maternity health record book.
It says her name is "Rin".
Nevertheless, we're talking about a 79-year-old man...
Well, setting aside the question
of what your father would or wouldn't have done,
I think you've gotta give him his props....
Daikichi, would you bring the cushions out of the closet for me?
Sure.
What?
Hey...
Let's swap!
No!
Leave it like it is!
I did it!
Hey, look! Look!
Reina, don't run!
Oh, how clever!
Is it pretty?
It certainly is! You're very good at cat's cradle, Reina-chan!
Next, try to make a four-square ladder!
Mmm...
Oh, my, Reina-chan... Here, let me show you...
Uh-uh!
Poop bomb!
Stop it this instant, Reina!
Uncle, Uncle...
Please, sleep ahead of me.
I'll take my turn watching the incense.
I-If you insist...
Hey, don't sleep in here!
Let's get some rest over there.
What about the incense?
Daikichi says he'll watch over it...
Oof...
Take care of my big brother...
You get some sleep over there, too.
I'm fine...
Look at that mug...
All right, everyone...
Please make your final farewells.
Rest in peace.
Big brother...
Grandpa...
I'll see you soon.
Come along, Reina.
Okay!
It's time to say goodbye to Grandpa.
Okay.
A field of flowers!
Stop it!
No! I'm making a field of flowers!
I wanna make it!
You, too, come over here and say goodbye.
You place these on Grandpa.
Hey!
Rindou...
[ Note: Rindou means Bellflower ]
Grandpa loved that flower...
That flower makes Grandpa the happiest.
He's not going to wake up again?
No. He's not going to wake up.
You really are Grandpa's child, aren't you?
Where did this "Yoshii Masako" go?
I don't think any good would come of finding the person
who abandoned her child and ran away.
How utterly irresponsible!
My big brother too was stubborn about it...
Watch it!
That girl can't talk!
It's a headache!
And she still has all of her baby teeth!
She can talk!
And she's not a headache!
She can not talk!
That's why it's so boring being with her!
Here! You can have all these if you go away!
You're like a candy shop owner!
Sorry, Dai-chan.
Setting aside the matter of future plans,
who's going to take care of that child right now?
Well, I can't.
Not with running the store...
If she were a little more proper...
And she seems to be suffering from delayed speech, too...
Mom...
You're at home. Why don't you take her in for a while?
Y-You know that'd be impossible!
I don't have that much free time on my hands!
Do you understand how hard it is to raise a child?!
Haven't I made enough sacrifices over the years?!
I'd feel sorry for the girl if she came over
and no one had time to look after her.
Wasn't this meeting supposed to be about who would take in Rin?
It's not like you have any intention of doing anything, do you, big brother?
Think about the situation a little more realistically.
In the first place, I'm not even certain that she is Grandpa's child.
See? You haven't thought it through so you can't even give me a comeback.
For now, I say we try placing her in a facility as quickly as possible...
What?!
Rin!
Wanna come home with me?
Hey! Daikichi!
Brother?!
Old man, I'm hungry...
O-Old man...?!
Don't call me "old man"!
After all, you're my aunt!
A sunny early Sunday afternoon
Let's go somewhere today
It's the same road I'm used to traveling
But I can see it sparkling so bright
With the sun shining down its warmth
And you here by my side...
I'm already high, high, high
I feel like dashing out
Sing, la, la, la
My voice out to forever
I'm already high, high, high
Ride the dancing wind
Sing, la, la, la
My voice springs up
Is it good?
Uh-huh.
More?
All we have left is rice.
I'll make a rice ball...
I don't have anything to put in the rice ball.
Salt!
Salt?
Hey! That's still hot!
Look!
But it'll have a tender taste.
Here, Grandpa.
I mean Daikichi!
Daikichi is strange too...
It's good.